A Finding Aid to the Janet De Coux Papers, 1895-2000, in the Archives of American Art AAA.decojane
Archives of American Art
Janet De Coux papers
1895-2000
AAA.decojane
Archives of American Art
3.9 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor Janet De Coux date from 1895-2000 and measure 3.9 linear feet. The collection documents De Coux's career through scattered biographical material, correspondence, audio cassette tapes of an autobiographical narrative, an interview transcript, miscellaneous notes and writings, sketchbooks and drawings, files for commissioned sculpture projects, printed material, photographs of De Coux, family members, friends, colleagues, and artwork.
De Coux, Janet
Provenance
The Janet De Coux papers were donated in 1992 by the artist and in two later installments in 2000-2001 by her longtime companion, Eliza Miller.
Related Material
Also found in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Janet De Coux done by George Gurney, May 5, 1978.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of this collection are available on 35mm microfilm reel 4909 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment. Glass plate negative housed separately and closed to researchers.
Biographical Note
Janet De Coux was born on October 5, 1904 in Niles, Michigan, the youngest of the five children of Bertha Wright De Coux and Rev. Charles John De Coux, an Episcopal clergyman. The family moved to Grand Rapids in 1908 and four years later to a farm in Gibsonia, outside Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.
De Coux studied with Joseph Bailey Ellis at the Carnegie Institute of Technology from 1925 to 1927. She then apprenticed in the New York studio of C. Paul Jennewein for fifteen months, followed by a year at the Gorham Bronze Division learning architectural modeling. She also worked with Aristide Cianfarani in Providence, and for Alvin Meyer in Chicago. While serving her apprenticeships, she attended night school at the New York School of Industrial Arts, the Rhode Island School of Design, and the Art Institute of Chicago. De Coux was then employed in James Earle Fraser's studio where she had previously assisted Gozo Kawamura.
In 1932 De Coux met Eliza Miller in the sculpture department of Carnegie Tech, beginning a sixty-year relationship in which they shared a shop and adjoining studios in Gibsonia, Pennsylvania. For several months in 1935, De Coux traveled to Germany, Italy, and Switzerland, where she joined her friend Aly Moore, the wife of sculptor Bruce Moore. She first met longtime friend Father Hughson on a ship returning to the United States from Europe.
A Guggenheim Fellowship awarded to De Coux in 1938 was renewed for a second year. In 1943, she became resident instructor at Cranbrook Academy of Art.
Janet De Coux died in December 1999.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of sculptor Janet De Coux measure 3.9 linear feet and date from 1895 to 2000. Found within the papers are scattered biographical material, including curriculum vitae and a file concerning De Coux's induction as a Distinguished Daughter of Pennsylvania. Correspondence is primarily between family, friends, and colleagues. It includes letters from Carl Milles, Bruce Moore, C.P. Jennewein, the Guild of Liturgy, Art and Design (GLAD), the Liturgical Arts Society, Inc., sculptor James Earle Fraser, offering advice on various sculpture projects, his wife Laura Gardin Fraser, a letter of congratulations from Paul Manship on the occasion of de Coux's election to the National Academy of Design, and approximately fifty letters, 1944-1952, from Anne Morrow Lindbergh, writer and wife of aviator Charles Lindbergh. There are also one or two letters from Lu Duble, Joseph Bailey Ellis, Mark Tobey, and Albert Wein.
Found within the papers are a transcript of an interview of De Coux by George Gurney, and audio cassettes with transcripts of an autobiographical narrative by De Coux. Miscellaneous notes and writings include autobiographical accounts and poems by De Coux and miscellaneous writings by others. Seven of De Coux's sketchbooks and a folder of drawings by De Coux, as well as a portrait of De Coux by C. Paul Jennewein are found in the Artwork series. Project files contain letters, receipts, clippings, brochures, and photographs for sculpture projects primarily commissioned by religious organizations. Printed material includes clippings, exhibition catalogs, and miscellaneous brochures. Photographs are of De Coux, family members, friends including Anne Morrow Lindbergh and her children, colleagues including James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, Carl Milles, and Bruce Moore, and sculpture.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series. Glass plate negative housed separately and closed to researchers.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1895-1993 (Box 1; 13 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1895-2000 (Boxes 1-2; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 3: Interviews, 1978, 1990 (Box 2; 3 folders)
Series 4: Notes and Writings, 1937-1996 (Box 2; 23 folders)
Series 5: Artwork, 1928-1929 (Boxes 2, 6; 9 folders)
Series 6: Project Files, 1942-1982 (Boxes 2-3, 6; 36 folders)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1906-2000 (Box 3; 20 folders)
Series 8: Photographs, 1926-1996 (Boxes 3-6, MGP 1; 1.3 linear feet)
Fraser, James Earle, 1876-1953; Fraser, Laura Gardin, 1889-1966; Guild of Liturgy, Art and Design; Gurney, George.; Jennewein, Carl Paul, 1890-; Lindbergh, Anne Morrow, 1906-; Liturgical Arts Society; Manship, Paul, 1885-1966; Milles, Carl, 1875-1955; Moore, Bruce, 1905-; Drawings; Interviews; Photographs; Poetry; Sketchbooks; Sound recordings
- Biographical Material, 1895-1993; Series 1; (Box 1; 13 folders)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes curriculum vitae, report cards, and passports. A file for the Distinguished Daughter of Pennsylvania Medal contains letters, a transcript of the ceremony, programs, directories, and photographs of the ceremony and other recipients including actress Grace Kelly. Miscellaneous family material includes a funeral card for De Coux's aunt Minnie, miscellaneous genealogical notes, and locks of De Coux's hair and her mother's hair.
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1944-1993; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Report Cards, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Passports, 1935-1984; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Award Certificates, 1954-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - File for Distinguished Daughter of Pennsylvania Medal, 1954-1955; (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 7-11)
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Material, 1895-1969, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
- Correspondence, 1895-2000; Series 2; (Boxes 1-2; 1.0 linear feet)
  Correspondence is primarily between De Coux and family members, friends including Anne Morrow Lindbergh, and colleagues including Abastenia St. Leger Eberle, James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, Camille Grapin, Carl Milles, and Bruce Moore. There are one or two letters each from Lu Duble, Joseph Bailey Ellis, Mark Tobey, and Albert Wein.
  Eleven letters from James Earle Fraser, two letters from Laura Gardin Fraser, and one letter from Paul Manship have been microfilmed on reel 4909, and are arranged together in one folder.
  - Eleven Letters from James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, and Paul Manship, 1935-1946; (see also reel 4909) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, undated; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Correspondence, 1895-1919 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1929; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21-23)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1931; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1934; (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 29-33)
  - Correspondence, 1935; (6 folders) (Box 1, Folder 34-39)
  - Correspondence, 1936; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1938; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1944; (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 49-52)
  - Correspondence, 1945; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 53-54)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1962; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 62-64)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Interviews, 1978, 1990; Series 3; (Box 2; 3 folders)
  This series consists of a transcript of an interview of De Coux conducted by George Gurney on May 5, 1978, and audiocassettes with transcripts of an autobiographical narrative by De Coux.
  - Transcript of Interview of Janet De Coux by George Gurney, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Audiocassettes of Autobiographical Narrative by De Coux, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Transcript of Autobiographical Narrative by De Coux, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Notes and Writings, 1937-1996; Series 4; (Box 2; 23 folders)
  This series includes miscellaneous notes and writings including autobiographical accounts and poems by De Coux. Miscellaneous writings by others include poems and a prayer written by De Coux's father, Charles J. De Coux.
  - Lists of Artwork, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pages from Exhibition Guest Book, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Autobiographical Writings by Janet De Coux, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Poems by De Coux, 1937-1938, undated; (8 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-24)
  - Notebook of Poems by De Coux, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Book Reviews by De Coux, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by De Coux, 1937-1991, undated; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
  - Poems by Charles J. De Coux, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Prayer by Charles J. De Coux, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Autobiographical Typescript by Bertha Wright De Coux, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Typescript ??Beloved and Lovely?? by Charles P. Price, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Typescript ??The Liberal Tradition of the Gospel?? by Charles P. Price, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Others, undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Artwork, 1928-1929; Series 5; (Boxes 2, 6; 9 folders)
  Artwork consists of sketchbooks and drawings including a pencil portrait of De Coux by C. Paul Jennewein.
  - Sketchbook 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Sketchbook 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Sketchbook 3, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sketchbook 4, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sketchbook 5, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Sketchbook 6, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Sketchbook 7, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Drawings, 1928, undated; (see also Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Oversized Pencil Portrait of Janet De Coux by C. Paul Jennewein, 1928 (Box 6 (sol))
- Project Files, 1942-1982; Series 6; (Boxes 2-3, 6; 36 folders)
  Project files contain letters, receipts, clippings, brochures, and photographs concerning sculpture projects primarily commissioned by religious organizations.
  - Bas-Relief for Post Office, Girard, Pennsylvania, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Statue of the Madonna, St. Mary Roman Catholic Church, Manhasset, New York, 1943-1946; (4 folders; see also Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 45-48)
  - Statue of St. Benedict, St. Vincent Archabbey, Latrobe, Pennsylvania, 1947-1949; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 49-52)
  - ??Luce Doors,?? St. Ann Chapel, Palo Alto, California, 1952; (see also Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Statue of the Madonna, Roman Catholic Church, Fishers Island, New York, 1955-1958; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
  - Altar, Crucifix, and Pyx for Order of St. Helena, Vails Gate, New York, 1959-1962; (8 folders) (Box 2, Folder 56-63)
  - Statue of William Penn, William Penn Memorial Museum, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, 1962-1970; (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 64-70)
  - Altar, Baptismal Font, and Crucifix, St. Stephen and Incarnation Episcopal Church, Washington, D.C., 1964-1967; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Statue of St. Stephen, St. Stephen Episcopal Church, Sweickley, Pennsylvania, 1968-1970; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
  - Bell Tower, Convent of St. Helena, Vails Gate, New York, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Two Oversized Photographs of Statue of the Madonna, St. Mary Roman Catholic Church, Manhasset, New York, 1943-1946 (Box 6 (sol))
  - Two Oversized Reproductions of Elevation Drawings, St. Ann Chapel, Palo Alto, California, 1952 (Box 6 (sol))
- Printed Material, 1906-2000; Series 7; (Box 3; 20 folders)
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition catalogs, reproductions of artwork, programs, a passenger list from De Coux's European trip, a high school yearbook, and miscellaneous brochures.
  - Clippings, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1906-1944 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1952-1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1980-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1944-1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by De Coux, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Reproductions of Artwork by Others, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Programs, 1911-1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Passenger List from the S. S. Washington, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Booklet of Transcript of Informal Talk by Carl Milles, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Book, The Poetry and Drawings by Janet De Coux, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - High School Yearbook, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Brochures, 1956-1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Photographs, 1926-1996; Series 8; (Boxes 3-6, MGP 1; 1.3 linear feet)
  Photographs are of De Coux, family members, friends including Anne Morrow Lindbergh and her children, colleagues including James Earle Fraser, Laura Gardin Fraser, Henry Kreis, Carl Milles, Bruce Moore, and students at Cranbrook Academy of Art, residences, De Coux's studio, and of an exhibition at the Carnegie Institute. Photographs are also of artwork for which project files were not created. Glass plate negative housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Photographs of Janet De Coux, 1926-1996, undated; (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 28-32)
  - Photographs of Family Members, undated; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Family Grave Sites, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Photographs of James Earle Fraser, Fraser??s Studio, Laura Gardin Fraser, Bruce Moore, and Henry Kreis, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Photographs of Anne Morrow Lindbergh and Children, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Photographs of Carl Milles, 1943, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Friends and Colleagues, 1943-1963, undated; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Photographs of Residences, 1953, undated; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 40-42)
  - Photographs of Studio, 1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Photographs of Exhibition at Carnegie Institute, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Bust Aaron, undated; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of Altar, Methodist Church, Brooklyn, Pennsylvania, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Photographs of Aumbry, Christ Church, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Christ and St. Paul, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Christ in the Garden, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of Busts Boy and Girl, undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of Statue Conversion of St. Paul, undated; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Photographs of Aluminum Crucifix, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Photographs of Cherrywood Crucifix, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Dancers, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Deposition of Christ, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Doubting Thomas, undated; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Photograph of Sculpture Eve, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Photographs of Model for a Fountain, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
    (1 glass plate negatives housed in MGP 1)
  - Photographs of Sculpture for the Hamm Memorial, undated; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 59-60)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture Jacob??s Dream, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Jesus and St. John, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Photographs of Bust John Lindsay, undated; (see also Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Judas, undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Madonna and Child, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Mother Earth, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Mother Seton, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Photograph of Relief Sculpture The Poet, undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Photographs of Incised Drawing on Slate Prodigal Son, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Prophet, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture Resurrection, undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Ruth and Naomi, undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture St. David and St. Paul, undated (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Photographs of Sanford Table, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Photographs of Relief Portrait Sarah Campbell De Coux, undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculptures The Swimmers or Night and Day, undated (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Woman Touching Christ??s Garment, undated (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Photographs of Sculpture John the Baptist, 1933 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Savanarola, 1933 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Deborah??s Song, 1938; (2 folders; see also Box 6) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 3-4)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture St. Angela and the Young Girl for the College of New Rochelle, New York, 1938; (see also Box 6) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture for the Food Building, New York World??s Fair, 1939 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Medal Thou Sluggard, 1942-1966 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Relief Portrait Elizabeth Morrow, 1945 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture Christ with the Children, Sacred Heart Primary School, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1947; (see also Box 6) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Sculpture, St. Scholastica Roman Catholic Church, Aspinwall, Pennsylvania, 1949-1950; (7 folders; see also Box 6) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 10-16)
  - Photographs of Charles Martin Hall Monument, 1953 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Crucifixion Group, 1953 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Photographs of Altar and Candlesticks, St. Margaret??s Hospital Chapel, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1955-1984; (2 folders) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 19-20)
  - Photographs of Altar and Crucifix, St. Barnabas Chapel, Gibsonia, Pennsylvania, 1956-1960; (3 folders) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 21-23)
  - Photographs of Altar and Hanging Cross, St. James Episcopal Church, Penn Hills, Pennsylvania, 1957 (Box 4 (hol), Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Sculpture for St. Thomas-in-the-Field Episcopal Church, Gibsonia, Pennsylvania, 1959; (2 folders) (Box 4 (hol), Folder 25-26)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Christ Sleeping in the Wilderness, Heckett Grave Marker, Butler, Pennsylvania, 1960 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Moses, 1960 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Head of Young Christ, St. Germaine Roman Catholic Church, Bethel Park, Pennsylvania, 1961 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Sculpture St. Boniface, Servants of the Most Holy Trinity Church, Silver Spring, Maryland, 1961 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Altar Cushions, 1962 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Altar, St. Paul's Episcopal Church, Southington, Connecticut, 1965 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 6)
  - Photograph of Neil Riley Vietnam Monument, 1966 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Marion and Paul Chalice and Pendant, 1968-1977 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture, Mars Middle School, Mars, Pennsylvania, 1970-1974 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Ceiling Sculpture, Architect??s Club, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1971 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Relief Sculpture, Indiana University of Pennsylvania, 1979 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Medal for the Society of Medalists, 1980 (Box 5 (pam), Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Sculpture Sarah and Abraham, 1986, undated (Box 5 (pam), Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Artwork by De Coux, 1960-1984, undated (2 folders) (See Also Box 6) (Box 5 (pam), Folder 14-15)
  - Photographs of Artwork by Others, undated (Box 5 (pam), Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 5 (pam), Folder 17)
  - Glass Plate Negative, 1 Glass negatives (Box MGP 1)
  - Oversized Photograph of the De Coux Family, undated (Box 6 (sol))
  - Oversized Photograph of Bust Aaron, undated (Box 6 (sol))
  - Oversized Photograph of Statue Conversion of St. Paul, undated (Box 6 (sol))
  - Two Oversized Photographs of Statue Doubting Thomas, undated (Box 6 (sol))
  - Two Oversized Photographs of Bust John Lindsay, undated (Box 6 (sol))
  - Oversized Photograph of Deborah??s Song, 1938 (Box 6 (sol))
  - Two Oversized Photographs of Relief Sculpture St. Angela and the Young Girl for the College of New Rochelle, New York, 1938 (Box 6 (sol))
  - Oversized Photograph of Relief Sculpture Christ with the Children, Sacred Heart Primary School, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1947 (Box 6 (sol))
  - Five Oversized Photographs of Sculpture, St. Scholastica Roman Catholic Church, Aspinwall, Pennsylvania, 1949-1950 (Box 6 (sol))
  - Oversized Photograph of Miscellaneous Artwork, Unidentified Sculpture by De Coux, undated (Box 6 (sol))